Guide to the Ray Benson Accessions
The Wittliff Collections
Ray Benson Accessions
1951-2018
The Wittliff Collections
Benson, Ray, 1951-
UPWC.18025
31.5 Linear Feet
28 boxes Framed items, posters, composite photograph, awards, artifacts
Ray Benson's archive contains materials documenting his entire career, featuring records, photographs, instruments, wardrobe, awards and other memorabilia dating from 1951-2018.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Ray Benson, 2017-2020
Biographical Notes
In a career that has spanned almost half a century, Benson has established himself as the modern king of Western Swing by being the driving force behind Asleep at the Wheel. In 1970 the Philadelphia-born Benson co-founded the band in Paw Paw, West Virginia along with Lucky Oceans and Leroy Preston. The band relocated to the Bay Area in 1971 upon the urging of musician Commander Cody, whose own band The Lost Planet Airmen was gaining prominence on the West Coast. Asleep at the Wheel quickly attracted fans, one of which was legendary rock and soul artist, Van Morrison. Soon after Morrison mentioned the band in an interview with Rolling Stone magazine, Asleep at the Wheel were offered a record contract by United Artists, and in 1973 their first album "Comin' Right At Ya" was released.
Not long after that, the "cosmic cowboys" of Texas came calling, and on the advice of artists like Willie Nelson and Doug Sahm, Benson moved the band to Austin. The rest, as they say, is history.
Benson's honors include 2011 Texan of the Year, 2011 Texas Medal of the Arts Award for Multimedia, the 2009 Lifetime Achievement Award from the Americana Music Association, the 2008 TEC Les Paul Award, and the official Texas State Musician in 2004. He's also an actor, writer and voice-over talent. A much sought after producer, he has worked with such artists as Willie Nelson, Aaron Neville, Aaron Watson and Suzy Bogguss, to name a few. Since 2010 Benson has hosted the highly successful "Texas Music Scene" television series which broadcasts weekly all across the country, showcasing live performances by today's talent in the Texas and Red Dirt music circuit. Benson has also hosted the radio show "Austin Outer Limits" on Sirius/XM's "Willie's Roadhouse" channel.
Scope and Contents
Ray Benson's archive contains materials documenting his entire career, featuring records, photographs, instruments, wardrobe, awards and other memorabilia dating from 1951-2018.
Western swing (Music); Country music; Benson, Ray, 1951-; Asleep at the Wheel (Musical group)
- Accession 2018-025, 12 Linear Feet Framed items and poster
  Abstract
  The Ray Benson archive includes material documenting Benson's music career from 1971-2017. Majority of the collection includes promotional articles, including an article from John Morthland; and awards. Included in the collection are photographs of Benson with President George W. Bush, Laura Bush, and others; Benson's boots and concert jacket; and correspondence with Dolly Parton and others. The folder titles preceding a semicolon reflect Benson's original descriptions.
  - "Ray Benson Promo Material"; Letters to Benson from Dolly Parton, Ann Richards, Jim Hightower, and others, 1979-2017 (Box 2647, Folder 1)
  - Cohen Family Timeline and Benson's childhood memorabilia, 1977-1998 (Box 2647, Folder 2)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel" black and blue XL shirt, undated (Box 2647, Folder 3)
  - "Live in Austin Since 1970" grey small shirt with red letters, undated (Box 2647, Folder 4)
  - "Willie & the Wheel starring Willie Nelson & Asleep at the Wheel" black small shirt, undated (Box 2647, Folder 5)
  - "The Kent Stage Presents: Hot Rod Lincoln 50th Anniversary Celebration" white shirt with blue and red picture, April 25, 2008 (Box 2647, Folder 6)
  - Academy of Country Music 32nd & 34th Annual Awards programs, including Rhythm & Blues Foundation 7th Annual Pioneer Awards discography, 1997-1999 (Box 2647, Folder 7)
  - Gear Patrol: The America Issue, undated (Box 2647, Folder 8)
  - Western Swing Monthly, American Classic Series, article from edibleaustin.com, and Capitol Tracks, 2000-2016 (Box 2647, Folder 9)
  - Event programs such as the 8th Annual SafePlace Anniversary Party, National Symphony Orchestra, and Encore: Fort Hays State University Encore Series, 2005-2010 (Box 2647, Folder 10)
  - 49th Annual Grammy Awards program, February 11, 2007 (Box 2647, Folder 11)
  - Programs for Trucker & Country Festival, Dallas Symphony Orchestra, and The University of Texas College of Fine Arts, 1995-2004 (Box 2647, Folder 12)
  - Articles about Ray Benson from Great Falls Tribune, Voice, and Billboard, 1978-2016 (Box 2647, Folder 13)
  - Publicity materials such as flyers, articles, programs, and newsletters, 2004-2010 (Box 2647, Folder 14)
  - Articles about Benson from San Antonio Express-News, Austin American- Statesman, Speilet, including publicity materials, 2004-2010 (Box 2647, Folder 15)
  - Publicity materials and advertisements such as Austin City Limits booklet, articles, and programs, 2000-2009 (Box 2647, Folder 16)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1976-77"; News clippings from Los Angeles Times, Arizona Republic, and Stereo Reviews, (1 of 2) (Box 2647, Folder 17)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1976-77"; News clippings from The Wichita Sun, The Dallas Morning News, and Rolling Stone, (2 of 2), 1976-1977 (Box 2647, Folder 18)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1991"; News clippings mostly pertaining to Dolly Parton and Benson's film Wild Texas Wind, (1 of 2), 1990-1991 (Box 2647, Folder 19)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1991"; News clippings mostly pertaining to Dolly Parton and Benson's film Wild Texas Wind, (2 of 2), 1990-1991 (Box 2648, Folder 1)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1996-1997"; Articles from Texas Monthly, The San Antonio Star, and The Austin Chronicle, 1996-1998 (Box 2648, Folder 2)
  - "AATW 25th Anniversary: Swingin' From Sept. 21-25, 1995"; (1 of 2) (Box 2648, Folder 3)
  - "AATW 25th Anniversary" Swingin' From Sept. 21-25, 1995"; (2 of 2) (Box 2648, Folder 4)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1993-94"; Articles from USA Today, St. Cloud's Times, and Los Angeles Times, (1 of 2), 1993-1995 (Box 2648, Folder 5)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1993-94"; Articles from Country Spirit, Country America, and Times Records News, (2 of 2), 1993-1995 (Box 2648, Folder 6)
  - The Austin Chronicle Songwriter Ray Benson award, 2007 (Box 2648, Folder 7)
  - Asleep at the Wheel's award nomination by the National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences for Best Country Instrumental Performance, February 17, 1991 (Box 2648, Folder 8)
  - Les Paul Award for Ray Benson, 2008 (Box 2648, Folder 9)
  - The Austin Chronicle award to Ray Benson, Record Producer, Reinventing the Wheel, 2007 (Box 2648, Folder 10)
  - The Austin Chronicle award to Ray Benson for Male Vocals, 2007 (Box 2648, Folder 11)
  - National Academy of Recording Arts & Science Awards for Ray Benson, 2005-2016 (Box 2648, Folder 12)
  - National Academy of Recording Arts & Sciences Awards for Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, 1992-2009 (Box 2648, Folder 13)
  - Grammy Magazine, letter to Benson on Grammy nomination, and special certificates order form, 1995-February 27, 2002 (Box 2649, Folder 1)
  - Letters from the White House, including a photo of Benson with Laura Bush, February 10, 1993-September 5, 2000 (Box 2649, Folder 2)
  - Texas Department of Protective and Regulatory Services certifate of appreciation, including drawings from children to Benson, September 16, 1992 (Box 2649, Folder 3)
  - Country Hall of Fame Award of Appreciation to Benson, including a letter from the Director, Kyle Young, October 18, 2000 (Box 2649, Folder 4)
  - Awards to Benson and Asleep at the Wheel such as Country Music Association Toys for Tots, State of Texas Second Legend of Texas swing, State of West Virginia, Smithsonian Appreciation, 1977-2013 (Box 2649, Folder 5)
  - Awards to Benson and Asleep at the Wheel such as Asleep at the Wheel Band Day, Country Music Foundation Certificate of Appreciation, Honorary Citizen Award, Academy of Recording Arts, 1985-2016 (Box 2649, Folder 6)
  - Texas Legislative Conference-Texan of the Year Reunion Program, Cowtown Society of Western Music Lifetime member, and 32nd Annual Grammy Awards booklet, February 21, 1990-March 17, 2016 (Box 2649, Folder 7)
  - Cowtown Society of Western Music's Western Swing Hero, 47th Annual Grammy nominee, and 52nd Grammy nominee medals, 2011 (Box 2649, Folder 8)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1978-86"; Articles about Asleep at the Wheel, (1 of 2), 1978-1987 (Box 2649, Folder 9)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1978-86"; Articles about Asleep at the Wheel, (2 of 2), 1978-1987 (Box 2649, Folder 10)
  - Articles on Asleep at the Wheel in The Rolling Stone, Dallas Morning News, and USA Today, 1975-1995 (Box 2649, Folder 11)
  - "Tribute [Preview]"; Asleep at the Wheel Tribute album information, 1993 (Box 2649, Folder 12)
  - "CBS Records Nashville"; Articles about Asleep at the Wheel from Austin American-Statesman, USA Today, and San Francisco Chronicle, 1987-1989 (Box 2649, Folder 13)
  - Asleep at the Wheel Tribute to the Music of Bob Wills and the Texas Playboys flyers, November 3, 1993 (Box 2649, Folder 14)
  - Asleep at the Wheel & Leon Rausch "It's a Good Day" info sheet and publicity info for Asleep at the Wheel's Tribute to Bob Wills and the Texas Playboys, November 3, 1993-July 20, 2010 (Box 2649, Folder 15)
  - "AATW Press-1999-2001"; Magazine and news articles from San Antonio Express-News, Billboard Magazine, and Chicago Tribune, (1 of 2) (Box 2649, Folder 16)
  - "AATW Press-1999-2001"; Magazine and news articles from San Antonio Express-News, Billboard Magazine, and Chicago Tribune, (2 of 2) (Box 2649, Folder 17)
  - DreamWorks Records Press Release for Asleep at the Wheel's documentary The Making of "Ride with Rob", July 24-26, 2000 (Box 2649, Folder 18)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1997-98"; Magazine and news articles from Arizona Republic, Billboard Magazine, and Austin American-Statesman, (1 of 2), 1996-1999 (Box 2649, Folder 19)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1997-98"; Magazine and news articles from Arizona Republic, Billboard Magazine, and Austin American-Statesman, (2 of 2), 1996-1999 (Box 2649, Folder 20)
  - Large Monthly Calendars, 1982-1988 (Box 2649, Folder 21)
  - Monthly Calendars, 1978-1991 (Box 2649, Folder 22)
  - Monthly and weekly calendars, 1988-1993 (Box 2650, Folder 1)
  - Monthly calendars, including notes within the calendars, 1976-1996 (Box 2650, Folder 2)
  - Monthly calendars for appointments, including notes, 1982-1994 (Box 2650, Folder 3)
  - Monthly calendars for appointments, 1983-1993 (Box 2650, Folder 4)
  - Monthly appointment books, including tour information, 1972-2001 (Box 2650, Folder 5)
  - Texas Music-Asleep at the Wheel license plate, undated (Box 2650, Folder 6)
  - Benson's badges for South by Southwest, KLRU, and Texas Legislative Conference, 2003 (Box 2650, Folder 7)
  - Bob Wills Fiddle Festival & Contest program and The 3rd Annual Ray Benson Birthday Bash laminated ticket/invite, March 14, 2006-October 18, 2015 (Box 2650, Folder 8)
  - Asleep at the Wheel cards, postcard, and Guest All Access badge, 1993 (Box 2650, Folder 9)
  - Asleep at the Wheel comic, CD set, and Smelly Tree ornament, November 13, 1990 (Box 2650, Folder 10)
  - Northwest Western Swing Music Society newsletter, Syracuse New Times, set lists, and Health Alliance for Austin Musicians Annual Report, 2008-2017 (Box 2650, Folder 11)
  - "Misc. Press Clippings"; Magazine and news clippings from Texas Monthly, Austin American-Statesman, and Austin Chronicle, 1985-2016 (Box 2650, Folder 12)
  - "1992 Press's Promo"; Photographs of Asleep at the Wheel and Benson, one photo by Brenda Ladd, circa 1992-April 20, 2001 (Box 2650, Folder 13)
  - Promo materials such as stickers; sheet music; Texas Medal of Arts Awards; and Certificate of Nomination for B. Iden Payne Award, 1985-2017 (Box 2650, Folder 14)
  - Photographs of Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, including two photos of Benson with Dolly Parton, 2002-2005 (Box 2650, Folder 15)
  - Group Golf photos from 10th Annual CARD Invitational BIGHORN Golf Club, and Tracy Byrd Celebrity Golf Tournament, October 5, 1998-November 28, 2001 (Box 2650, Folder 16)
  - Well Aware, Inc. and the Maasai People of Kenya appreciation award, August 6, 2006 (Box 2650, Folder 17)
  - Asleep at the Wheel induction into the Reagan Watson Alumni Association certificate, March 15, 2008 (Box 2650, Folder 18)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1989-94"; Magazine and news clippings from Austin American-Statesman, The Rolling Stone, and MIX, (1 of 2), 1989-1995 (Box 2651, Folder 1)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1989-94"; Magazine and news clippings from Austin American-Statesman, The Rolling Stone, and MIX, (2 of 2), 1989-1995 (Box 2651, Folder 2)
  - "Press Binders"; Magazine and news clippings, including press forms, (1 of 2), 1999-2001 (Box 2651, Folder 3)
  - "Press Binders"; Magazine and news clippings, including press forms, (2 of 2), 1991-2001 (Box 2651, Folder 4)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1995 & 1996"; Magazine and news clippings from Country Music, Dallas Morning News, and San Antonio Express-News, 1993-1996 (Box 2651, Folder 5)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1971-73"; News clippings from Washington Star, The Daily Californian, and Austin American-Statesman, (1 of 2), 1971-1973 (Box 2651, Folder 6)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1971-73"; News clippings from Washington Star, The Daily Californian, and Austin American-Statesman, (2 of 2), 1971-1973 (Box 2651, Folder 7)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1974-75"; News clippings from The Houston Post, Music City News, and Billboard, (1 of 2), 1972-1975 (Box 2651, Folder 8)
  - "Asleep at the Wheel Press 1974-75"; News clippings from The Houston Post Music City News, and Billboard, (2 of 2), 1972-1975 (Box 2651, Folder 9)
  - 1979 Monthly Minder for concert planning (Box 2651, Folder 10)
  - Exhibit labels from the temporary 2017 Ray Benson exhibition (Box 2651, Folder 11)
  - Black and white group photo of Asleep at the Wheel on exhibit board, including Benson's graduation photo, undated (Box 2651, Folder 12)
  - Asleep at the Wheel Tribute to the Music of Bob Wills CD booklet, National Academy of Recording Arts & Sciences nomination letter, and Austin City Limits 25th Anniversary Special letter, 1993-1995 (Box 2651, Folder 13)
  - National Academy of Recording Arts & Sciences nomination for Asleep at the Wheel with Lyle Lovett, including Texas Senate's appreciation award for participation in Texas Sesquicentennial, 1986-1994 (Box 2651, Folder 14)
  - Framed, The Keystone State League, Inc. Football Registration and Identification card, undated (Box 2651, Folder 15)
  - Framed photograph of Ray Benson playing the guitar, July 8, 2015 (Box 2651, Folder 16)
  - Rhythm & Blues Foundation Benefit Concert, blue large t-shirt, May 28, undated (Box 2651, Folder 17)
  - 2014 Telly Award "The Texas Music Scene" General Entertainment (Box 2652, Item 1)
  - 2007 Community Hero Award for Ray Benson, SafePlace Celebration, October 2, 2007 (Box 2652, Item 2)
  - 2001 Telly Award, Ray Benson/Producer Asleep at the Wheel "Ride with Bob" (Box 2652, Item 3)
  - Ray Benson, Member, AMD64 Premier Artist, undated (Box 2652, Item 4)
  - Benson's boots, undated (Box 2653)
- Accession 2018-078, 12 Linear Feet
  Archival materials donated by musician, Ray Benson, as additions to his collection following his music career from 1957-2015. Majority of the addition are photographs of Asleep at the Wheel and headshots of Benson; news clippings and magazine articles on Asleep at the Wheel; and concert promotional materials such as posters and flyers. Included in the collection are handwritten song lyrics; Benson's guitar, cowboy hat, and concert shirt; and photographs of Benson with former U.S. Presidents Bill Clinton, George W. Bush, and Barack Obama.
  - Official newsletters of Asleep at the Wheel Fan Club, As the Wheel Turns, 1995-2002 (Box 2809, Folder 1)
  - Postcards from Asleep at the Wheel, album covers for Asleep at the Wheel's Tribute to the Music of Bob Willis and the Texas Playboys, 1993-2017 (Box 2809, Folder 2)
  - Comin' Right at Ya promotional sheets, articles about Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, and photographs of Asleep at the Wheel, 1994-2015 (Box 2809, Folder 3)
  - Black and white photographs of Asleep at the Wheel, one taken by Buddy Lee, in a 25th Anniversary folder, 1970-1995 (Box 2809, Folder 4)
  - Three 25th Anniversary folders holding black and white photos of Asleep at the Wheel, 1970-1995 (Box 2809, Folder 5)
  - Black and white photographs of Asleep at the through the years, undated (Box 2809, Folder 6)
  - Country Music People, Texas Music, and American Profile magazines with Benson on the cover, including concert poster, 1992-2011 (Box 2809, Folder 7)
  - Wooden Texas shaped award for Asleep at the Wheel for giving to the KPFT's Cosmic Cowboy Benefit Concerts, undated (Box 2809, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence such as from U.S. House of Representative Chief of Staff, John Lawrence; Tim and Faith McGraw; and Texas State University's President, Denise Trauth, 2011-2015 (Box 2809, Folder 9)
  - Annotated handwritten song lyrics such as "Lets Forget About [Tomorrow] Today", and "Gimme Some Peace, Gimme Some Rest", May 4, 2016 (Box 2809, Folder 10)
  - Capitol Tracks, correspondence from Luci Baines Johnson and William Powers Jr., and Country Music Awards "The Bicentennial Year" Top Progressive Group award, 1976-2014 (Box 2809, Folder 11)
  - Photographs of Benson with others such as Pamela Anderson, Lyle Lovett, a former Texas Governor, Rick Perry, 1997-1998 (Box 2809, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, Bohemian Grove 2012 Schedule of Events, and 2nd Annual Ray Benson Birthday Bash lanyard, 2005-2015 (Box 2809, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence including letters from The White House, photograph of Benson performing with Dolly Parton, and articles on Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, 2001-2015 (Box 2809, Folder 14)
  - American Profile, University of Texas Press catalog, and Austin Seniors' Guide, 2011-2015 (Box 2809, Folder 15)
  - San Antonio Magazine, Texas Music, Texas Monthly, and The Journal of Texas Music History, 2009-2013 (Box 2809, Folder 16)
  - Texas Medal of Arts Awards materials, 2011-2015 (Box 2809, Folder 17)
  - Graham Concert Association, Million Dollar Quartet Playbill, and Fender Certificate of Authenticity for a Vintage Telecaster Guitar, 1988-2015 (Box 2809, Folder 18)
  - Photograph of Benson with Ann Richards, undated (Box 2809, Folder 19)
  - Photograph of Benson with President George W. Bush, signed by President George W. Bush, framed, undated (Box 2809, Folder 20)
  - Photograph of Benson with President Bill Clinton, undated (Box 2809, Folder 21)
  - Photograph of Benson with President Barack Obama, undated (Box 2809, Folder 22)
  - Asleep at the Wheel with special guest Kinky Friedman and the Texas Cowboys poster, undated (Box 2809, Folder 23)
  - Black and white photograph of Ray Benson, framed, undated (Box 2809, Folder 24)
  - Black and white photograph of young Ray Benson and other children, framed, undated (Box 2809, Folder 25)
  - "Fat Boy Rag", "House of Blue Lights", "The Letter That Johnny Walker Read", "Before You Stopped Loving Me", and "Quittin' Time" Asleep at the Wheel 45's, 1972-1990 (Box 2809, Folder 26)
  - Open reel recordings of "Choo Choo Choo Boogie", "Don't Roll Them Bloodshot Eyes at Me", "Don't Ask Me Why I'm Going to Texas", "Our Names Aren't Mentioned (Together Anymore)", "Last Night I Shot Myself", "Jumpin' at the [Blood side]", and "Miss Molly", June 11-17, 1973 (Box 2810, Folder 1)
  - "Black and White Rag" and "Dusty Boots" Asleep at the Wheel 45s, (1 of 2), undated (Box 2810, Folder 2)
  - "Black and White Rag" and "Dusty Boots" Asleep at the Wheel 45s, (2 of 2), undated (Box 2810, Folder 3)
  - Open reel recordings from Jack Clement Recording Studios of songs such "Route 66", "Cajun Stripper", "Lost Mino", "Miles & Miles of Texas", and "If I Can't Love You", April 21, 1976 (Box 2810, Folder 4)
  - Black cap with orange, white, and black lettering stating "Ray Benson ASCAP Birthday Bash", undated (Box 2810, Folder 5)
  - Black cap with red and white Asleep at the Wheel-since 1970 logo, undated (Box 2810, Folder 6)
  - Orange cap with blue lettering which states "ASCAP Ray Benson Birthday Bash", undated (Box 2810, Folder 7)
  - Blue cap with white lettering stating "Big Balls in Cowtown-Asleep at the Wheel", undated (Box 2810, Folder 8)
  - Orange cap with white and black lettering that states "Ray Benson-ASCAP-Birthday Bash", undated (Box 2810, Folder 9)
  - Music award and concert memorabilia such as Core Values Awards, Jazz San Javier, Austin City Limits pass, and "A Ride with Bob", 1993-2010 (Box 2811, Folder 1)
  - Acoustic Guitar with a post-it on page 38 on "Cindy Walker 1918-2006, July 2006 (Box 2811, Folder 2)
  - "A Ride with Bob: From Austin to Tulsa", photography by Brio Yiapan, booklet of photos from the production, March 5, 2005 (Box 2811, Folder 3)
  - Texas Music, Texas Monthly, and The Journal of Texas Music History, 2007-2009 (Box 2811, Folder 4)
  - "Lyrics & CD for Willie Session 8/5 & 8/6", undated (Box 2811, Folder 5)
  - Handwritten song lyrics of "Wheel Keeps on Rollin'", "Quitin' Time", "Hot Rod Lincoln", "Don't Let Go", undated (Box 2811, Folder 6)
  - Contracts and receipt with Washburn; Texas State Agenda; and certificate of Nomination for B. Iden Payne Award, 1989-2005 (Box 2811, Folder 7)
  - Photographs of Ray Benson performing, advertisements to concerts, "A Ride with Bob" booklets, and annotated "Gone But Not Forgotten" lyrics, 2004-2009 (Box 2811, Folder 8)
  - Best in Texas: Music Magazine, Country Line Magazine, KITSAP Sun, Austin American-Statesman, and The Washington Post, 2004-2009 (Box 2811, Folder 9)
  - Texas Festival at the Kennedy Center photograph, June 11-22, 1991 (Box 2811, Folder 10)
  - Asleep at the Wheel's The Wheel Keeps On Rollin' and CD booklet for Texas Gold and Comin' Right at Ya, 1995-2000 (Box 2811, Folder 11)
  - California State Senate's Certificate of Recognition, Senate of the State of Texas certificate that the Texas flag was presented to Asleep at the Wheel's 25th Anniversary, and City of Austin Proclamation, 1994-1995 (Box 2811, Folder 12)
  - Country Music Association awards for Benson as producer and Asleep at the Wheel, including childhood photo of Benson at Millshade Day Camp, 1957-1994 (Box 2811, Folder 13)
  - City of Austin Proclamation for Asleep at the Wheel Day, August 31, 1999 (Box 2811, Folder 14)
  - Concert and award memorabilia for The Texas Film Hall of Fame, Austin City Limits Festival, George Strait Country Music Festival, and SXSW, 2004-2015 (Box 2811, Folder 15)
  - Articles on Benson, The National Academy of Recording Arts and Sciences, Inc. nomination to Asleep at the Wheel, Benson's Honorary Junior Member, and photo of Benson, 1988-2006 (Box 2811, Folder 16)
  - Handwritten song lyrics such as "Marie", "Jingle Bell Boogie", "Rodeo Song", "Hey Baby Kep-Pa-So", "I Wish You Knew", and "Smoke, Smoke, Smoke", undated (Box 2811, Folder 17)
  - "Photo Negatives"; 8"x10" photos of Benson and Asleep at the Wheel, including photos of Asleep at the Wheel with Dolly Parton, undated (Box 2811, Folder 18)
  - White container titled "Ray" containing photos of Benson, 1996 (Box 2811, Folder 19)
  - Photographs of Asleep at the Wheel and fans, including photo of musician, Shorty Holloway, 1996-1997 (Box 2811, Folder 20)
  - Postcard about proposed "Behind the Scenes" E! episode for Benson's Route 66 Tour, 1992 (Box 2811, Folder 21)